Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 1971; 5 (Box 1550)
    - Verso: Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, Texas Apollo 15 Eva----Astronaut James B. Irwin, lunar module pilot, works at the Lunar Roving vehicle during the first Apollo 15 lunar surface extravehicular activity (EVA-1) at the Headley-Apennie landing site. The shadow of the Lunar Module "Falcon" is in the foreground. This view is looking northeast, with Mount Hadley in the background. This photograph was taken by Astronaut David R. Scott, commander, 1-verso
    - Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, Texas Apollo 15 EVA photo-Astronaut David R. Scott, commander, standing on the slope of Hadley Delta, uses a 70 mm camera during Apollo 15 extravehicular activity (EVA) on the lunar surface. He is some 10.5 miles (or 17.5 kilometers) from the base of the Apennine Mountains seen in the background. Scott carries tongs in his left hand. The Lunar Roving Vehicle (LRV) or Rover is in the background. This view is looking east, 2
    - Verso: Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, Texas Apollo 15 EVA photo-Astronaut David R. Scott, commander, standing on the slope of Hadley Delta, uses a 70 mm camera during Apollo 15 extravehicular activity (EVA) on the lunar surface. He is some 10.5 miles (or 17.5 kilometers) from the base of the Apennine Mountains seen in the background. Scott carries tongs in his left hand. The Lunar Roving Vehicle (LRV) or Rover is in the background. This view is looking east, 2-verso
    - Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, Texas Apollo 15 EVA photograph---Astronaut James B. Irwin, lunar module pilot, gives a military salute while standing beside the deployed U.S. flag during the Apollo 15 lunar surface extravehicular activity at eh Hadley-Apennine landing site. The flag was deployed toward the end of EVA-2. The Lunar Module "Falcon" is in the center. On the right is the Lunar Roving Vehicle. This view is looking almost due south. Hadley Delta in the background rises approximately 4,000 meters (about 13, 124 feet) above the plain. The base of the mountain is approximately 5 kilometers (about 3 statute miles) away. This photograph was taken by Astronaut David R. Scott, Apollo 15 commander, 3
    - Verso: Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, Texas Apollo 15 EVA photograph---Astronaut James B. Irwin, lunar module pilot, gives a military salute while standing beside the deployed U.S. flag during the Apollo 15 lunar surface extravehicular activity at eh Hadley-Apennine landing site. The flag was deployed toward the end of EVA-2. The Lunar Module "Falcon" is in the center. On the right is the Lunar Roving Vehicle. This view is looking almost due south. Hadley Delta in the background rises approximately 4,000 meters (about 13, 124 feet) above the plain. The base of the mountain is approximately 5 kilometers (about 3 statute miles) away. This photograph was taken by Astronaut David R. Scott, Apollo 15 commander, 3-verso
    - Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, Texas Apollo 15 EVA photo----Astronaut James B. Irwin, lunar module pilot, walks away from the Lunar Roving Vehicle during the third Apollo 15 lunar surface extravehicular activity (EVA-3) at the Hadley-Apennine landing site. The Rover is parked a short distance from the rim of Hadley Rille. The far wall of the rille is in the distance at the extreme upper left. Irwin is holding the 500m Hasselblad camera in his left hand. This photograph was taken by Astronaut David R. Scott, commander, 4
    - Verso: Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, Texas Apollo 15 EVA photo----Astronaut James B. Irwin, lunar module pilot, walks away from the Lunar Roving Vehicle during the third Apollo 15 lunar surface extravehicular activity (EVA-3) at the Hadley-Apennine landing site. The Rover is parked a short distance from the rim of Hadley Rille. The far wall of the rille is in the distance at the extreme upper left. Irwin is holding the 500m Hasselblad camera in his left hand. This photograph was taken by Astronaut David R. Scott, commander, 4-verso
  - Subject files: National Association of Broadcasters (NAB Award), 1968; 6 (Box 1550)
    - [Lowell Thomas, right, President Lyndon Baines Johnson, second from right], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas, right, President Lyndon Baines Johnson, left], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and President Lyndon Baines Johnson, center], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man at the National Association of Broadcasters event], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving a reward at the National Association of Broadcasters event], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas on stage at the National Association od Broadcasters event], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and two other men applauding at a National Associations of Broadcasters event], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas with other members of the National Association of Broadcasters], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas in line with other memebers of the National Association of Broadcasters], 9
  - Subject files: National Association of Broadcasters (NAB Award) [color photographs], 1968; 7 (Box 1550)
    - [National Association of Broadcasters event to present the NAB Award], 1
    - [National Association of Broadcasters event to present NAB Award], 2
  - Subject files: Near East Foundation, 1966; 8 (Box 1550)
    - Note: [letter to Lowell Thomas from Lindsley Schepnoes, Assistant to the President of the Near East Foundation concerning photographs], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man and a woman involved with the Near East Foundation], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and two women involved with the Near East Foundation], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with people involved with the Near East Foundation], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with Ambassador Rashid Al-Rashid of Kuwait, with Ambassador Muhammad H. El-Farra the Jordanian representative to the United Nation and Ambassador Louis Ignacio-Pinto from Dahomey and unidentified man], 5
    - Note: [letter to Lowell Thomas from E. DeAlton Partridge, President of the Near East Foundation describing the figures in photograph 8.5], 6
  - Subject files: Jawaharlal Nehru, circa 1950s; 9 (Box 1550)
    - L.T. and Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru, 1
    - Verso: L.T. and Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru, 1-verso
    - With Nehru in New Delhi, 2
    - Verso: With Nehru in New Delhi, 2-verso
    - With Nehru in New Delhi, 3
  - Subject files: Nepal (coronation ceremony of King Mahendra), 1956; 10 (Box 1550)
    - Mahendra Bin Bikram, Shah Deva in his coronation crown, Katmandu, Nepal, 1955 [1956?]; LT was the US Ambassador to the coronation. Jewels in crown worth many millions. Feathers of the Greater Bird of Paradise. (Only the king and queen of Nepal can wear them. Many years ago the nations united in forbidding women wearing them because the birds of paradise in New Guinea were almost extinct.), 1
    - Verso: Mahendra Bin Bikram, Shah Deva in his coronation crown, Katmandu, Nepal, 1955 [1956?]; LT was the US Ambassador to the coronation. Jewels in crown worth many millions. Feathers of the Greater Bird of Paradise. (Only the king and queen of Nepal can wear them. Many years ago the nations united in forbidding women wearing them because the birds of paradise in New Guinea were almost extinct.), 1-verso
    - [Coronation ceremony of King Mahendra], 2
    - [Coronation ceremony of King Mahendra], 3
    - [An officer on a horse at the coronation ceremony of King Mahendra of Nepal], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas standing next to a woman and man shaking hands at the coronation ceremony of King Mahendra of Nepal], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas standing next to a woman and man shaking hands at the coronation ceremony of King Mahendra of Nepal], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas watching as two women shake hands at the coronation ceremony of King Mahendra of Nepal], 7
    - [People in line to shake hands at the coronation ceremony of King Mahendra of Nepal], 8
    - [A line of people waiting to shake hands at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas waiting in line to shake hands at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 10
    - [People shaking hands at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a man at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 12
    - [Women sitting at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 13
    - [Women sitting around a table at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 14
    - [A group of women chatting at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 15
    - [Two men talking at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 16
    - [Two men talking at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 17
    - [Two men at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 18
    - [Men talking at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 19
    - [Men talking at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 20
    - [People talking at the coronation ceremony of King Mehendra of Nepal], 21
  - Subject files: New Guinea trip [Lowell Thomas and Frances Ryan Thomas], circa 1950s; 11 (Box 1550)
    - [Lowell Thomas and Frances Ryan and others during a trip to New Guinea], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas and Fracnes Ryan with friends during their trip to New Guinea], 2
  - Subject files: New Years, circa 1940s; 12 (Box 1550)
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking a man's hand on New Years], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking a mans hand on New Years], 2
  - Subject files: Electra Nicks, undated; 13 (Box 1550)
    - [Electra Nicks and two others], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas with Electra Nicks (?)], 2
    - [Electra Nicks (?) crossing the street], 3
    - [Electra Nicks and Lowell Thomas talking at an event], 4
    - [Electra Nicks and another woman sitting on a couch], 5
    - [Electra Nicks and Lowell Thomas at an event], 6
  - Subject files: President Richard M. Nixon (San Clemente, California) [includes color photographs], circa 1970s; 14 (Box 1550)
    - [From left to right: Tom Kelland, Glenn Campbell, Dan McMichael, Lowell Thomas, Allen Hoover, Hon. Richard M. Nixon, Captain Bob Swain, George Russell, and Tom Sunderland], 1
    - Verso: From left to right: Tom Kelland, Glenn Campbell, Dan McMichael, Lowell Thomas, Allan Hoover, Hon. Richard M. Nixon, Captain Bob Swain, George Russell, Tom Sunderland., 1-verso
    - [President Richard Nixon eating lunch with a group of people], 2
    - [President Richard Nixon having lunch with Lowell Thomas and others], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas, President Richard Nixon and others enjoying lunch outdoors], 4
    - [President Richard Nixon with Lowell Thomas and others eating lunch], 5
    - [President Richard Nixon standing with a group of people], 6
    - [President Richard Nixon having lunch], 7
    - [President Richard Nixon standing with four others], 8
    - [President Richard Nixon and company having lunch], 9
    - [Guitarist playing music for President Richard Nixon and others while they eat], 10
    - [Man giving President Richard Nixon pita bread (?)], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas and President Richard Nixon making drinks], 12
    - [Man giving President Richard Nixon pita bread (?)], 13
    - [Lunch with President Richard Nixon and others], 14
    - [Outdoor lunch with President Richard Nixon and others], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas and President Richard Nixon making drinks], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with President Richard Nixon and another man], 17
  - Subject files: Tenzing Norgay [Tenzing Norkey], 1971; 15 (Box 1550)
    - Caption: To my friend Lowell Thomas, Tashi Deli, [signed] Tenzing, 1
  - Subject files: North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) satellite photographs, circa 1970; 16 (Box 1550)
    - Caption: Appearing to be hanging upside down in space, 1
    - Caption: 400,000 "Space" miles on the ground, 2
    - Caption: Earth Protection for a space vehicle, 3
  - Subject files: Olympics, 1968; 17 (Box 1550)
    - Hack Miller [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Hack Miller, 1-verso
    - Hack Miller, 2
    - Verso: Hack Miller, 2-verso
    - Hack Miller Desert News, 3
    - Verso: Hack Miller Desert News, 3-verso
    - Hack Miller, 4
    - Verso: Hack Miller, 4-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with Hack Miller (?)], 5
  - Subject files: Olympics trophy, circa 1930s; 18 (Box 1550)
    - [Lowell Thomas with Olympic awards], [3 copies], 1
  - Subject files: Captain Rex Palmer, undated; 19 (Box 1550)
    - Captain Red Palmer Man I flew with in 1917 at Kantara filming the Suez Canal. He had been a test pilot. After the war he became famous in England on the BBC for his program for children. He was known as Uncle Rex. He was the second airman whom I flew The first havin been the South African Major Emmett........., 1
    - Note: Captain Red Palmer Man I flew with in 1917 at Kantara filming the Suez Canal. He had been a test pilot. After the war he became famous in England on the BBC for his program for children. He was known as Uncle Rex. He was the second airman whom I flew The first havin been the South African Major Emmett........., 2
  - Subject files: Pan America flight (United States Army), 1926 - 1927; 20 (Box 1550)
    - Haitian and American officials at departure of around America Flyers, Monday April 18 1927, 1
    - Note: Haitian and American officials at departure of around America Flyers, Monday April 18 1927, 2
    - This is a view of Sao Paulo taken from a considerable height, above the aviation field of Forca Publica looking toward the south. In the left foreground is the River Tiete, 3
    - Note: This is a view of Sao Paulo taken from a considerable height, above the aviation field of Forca Publica looking toward the south. In the left foreground is the River Tiete, 4
    - This is a glimpse of the suburb of Perdizes in the western part of Sao Paulo City, 5
    - Note: This is a glimpse of the suburb of Perdizes in the western part of Sao Paulo City, 6
    - This is another view of Sao Paulo from above the clouds, looking more to the east, 7
    - Note: This is another view of Sao Paulo from above the clouds, looking more to the east, 8
    - View of the center of the City of Sao Paulo looking toward the east, 9
    - Note: View of the center of the City of Sao Paulo looking toward the east, 10
    - Copacabana Beach and Hotel. Rio de Janeiro., 11
    - Note: Copacabana Beach and Hotel. Rio de Janeiro., 12
    - Naval Baser, facing WSW. Rio de Janeiro., 13
    - Note: Naval Baser, facing WSW. Rio de Janeiro., 14
    - Copacabana Beach (left background), Morro da Babylonia in foreground; facing WSW from Morro da Urca., 15
    - Note: Copacabana Beach (left background), Morro da Babylonia in foreground; facing WSW from Morro da Urca., 16
    - Caption: Praca de Copocabsns, facing southwest. Note: Copacabana Beach and Hotel. Rio de Janeiro., 17
    - Note: Copacabana Beach and Hotel. Rio de Janeiro., 18
    - Caption: Caminho Aereo Pao de Assucar Rio de Janeiro; Facing Northeast. Dangerous because hard to see., 19
    - [Rio de Janeiro. Brasil. Pan de Azucar], 20
    - Arrival of around American Flyers at Port au Prince. Saturday April 16, 1927, Dr. Beebe's ship in background, 21
    - Note: Arrival of around American Flyers at Port au Prince. Saturday April 16, 1927, Dr. Beebe's ship in background, 22
    - M. Delva - Mayor of Port au Prince greeting around American Flyers upon their arrival. Saturday April 16, 1927, 23
    - Note: M. Delva - Mayor of Port au Prince greeting around American Flyers upon their arrival. Saturday April 16, 1927, 24
    - Photograph of President Borno and around America Flyers - a moment before their departure for Cuba. Monday April 18, 1927, 25
    - Note: Photograph of President Borno and around America Flyers - a moment before their departure for Cuba. Monday April 18, 1927, 26
    - Planes of around America Flyers at Port au Prince., 27
    - Note: Planes of around America Flyers at Port au Prince., 28
    - El New York y el St. Louis Amarizando, 29
    - Los Aviones a la vista, 30
    - Caption: Raid Panamericans Puerto Cabello, Pto[?] de La Borburata donde Elegaron[?] aviones;Verso: Puerto Cabello Maj. Dargue, 31
    - Verso: Puerto Cabello Maj. Dargue, 31-verso
    - Caption: La Aviacion Norte Americana en Pto-Cabello; Verso: Puerto cabello Maj. Dargue., 32
    - Verso: Puerto cabello Maj. Dargue., 32-verso
    - [Pilot of the Pan American flight], 33
    - Return to Mrs. Benton; Mollendo, 34
    - Verso: Return to Mrs. Benton; Mollendo, 34-verso
    - El Almuerzo de los Aviadores, 35
    - Return to Mrs. Benton; Mollendo, 36
    - Verso: Return to Mrs. Benton; Mollendo, 36-verso
    - Return to Mrs. Benton; Pulling the San Francisco out of mud at Tampico, 37
    - Verso: Return to Mrs. Benton; Pulling the San Francisco out of mud at Tampico, 37-verso
    - Caption: San Jose C.R. - Cosechando caf - Picking Coffee, 38
    - Verso: Return to Mrs. Benton, 38-verso
    - The traffic in the principal Avenues, Guayaquil., 39
    - Verso: The traffic in the principal Avenues, Guayaquil., 39-verso
    - Woolsley + Benton of Pan American flight Killed in Buenos Aries 2/26/27 (Photo from Mrs. Woolsey), 40
    - Verso: Woolsley + Benton of Pan American flight Killed in Buenos Aries 2/26/27 (Photo from Mrs. Woolsey), 40-verso
  - Subject files: Pan America flight (United States Army), 1926 - 1927; 21 (Box 1550)
    - The Star Spangled Banner at Bolling Field as the P.A.F. was landing, 1
    - Verso: The Star Spangled Banner at Bolling Field as the P.A.F. was landing, 1-verso
    - Port-au-Prince, Haiti., 2
    - Verso: Port-au-Prince, Haiti., 2-verso
    - We brought back letters from the Presidents of various republics for President Coolidge Bolling Field May 2, 3
    - Verso: We brought back letters from the Presidents of various republics for President Coolidge Bolling Field May 2, 3-verso
    - Indian Shrine, Peru, 4
    - Verso: Indian Shrine, Peru, 4-verso
    - La Paz, Bolivia, with snow-covered [illegible] in the background, 5
    - Verso: La Paz, Bolivia, with snow-covered [illegible] in the background, 5-verso
    - A slight accident to the Detroit at Mar del Plata, Argentina., 6
    - Verso: A slight accident to the Detroit at Mar del Plata, Argentina., 6-verso
    - The funeral procession in B/a [Burnos Aries?] President Alvear + Secretary of War in lead, walking, 7
    - Verso: The funeral procession in B/a [Burnos Aries?] President Alvear + Secretary of War in lead, walking, 7-verso
    - Coming ashore ar Pocitos Beach, Montevideo, 8
    - Verso: Coming ashore ar Pocitos Beach, Montevideo, 8-verso
    - Reception at country club, Rio de Janiero, 9
    - Verso: Reception at country club, Rio de Janiero, 9-verso
    - Refueling at Cayenne, 10
    - Verso: Refueling at Cayenne, 10-verso
    - Caption: U.S. Army Pan-American Flight, 11
    - Grass boat on Lake Titicaca, Peru, 12
    - Verso: Grass boat on Lake Titicaca, Peru, 12-verso
    - Caption: U.S. Army Pan-American Fliers, 13
    - Arrival in B.a., 14
    - Verso: Arrival in B.a., 14-verso
    - At the military school, Caracas, Venez., 15
    - Verso: At the military school, Caracas, Venez., 15-verso
    - at Point Isabel, Texas [on same sheet as 21.17], 16
    - Verso: at Point Isabel, Texas, 16-verso
    - at Point Isabel, Texas [on same sheet as 21.16], 17
    - Verso: at Point Isabel, Texas, 17-verso
    - Port Isabel, Tex [on same sheet as 21.19], 18
    - Verso: Port Isabel, Tex, 18-verso
    - Port Isabel, Tex [on same sheet as 21.18], 19
    - Verso: Port Isabel, Tex, 19-verso
    - President Leguia of Peru at the flying field at Las Palmas, 20
    - Verso: President Leguia of Peru at the flying field at Las Palmas, 20-verso
    - Casa de Espana, our "Rome" while in Caracas, Venez., 21
    - Verso: Casa de Espana, our "Rome" while in Caracas, Venez., 21-verso
    - Dinner by Consil (U.S.) Wood at Vera Cruz, 22
    - Verso: Dinner by Consil (U.S.) Wood at Vera Cruz, 22-verso
    - Reception by Mayor of Anrquipa, 23
    - Verso: Reception by Mayor of Anrquipa, 23-verso
    - A hard looking lot after flying across the jungles of the Amazon months. Taken on back at Cayenne, 24
    - Verso: A hard looking lot after flying across the jungles of the Amazon months. Taken on back at Cayenne, 24-verso
    - [Plane of the U.S. Army Pan-American Flight], 25
    - Caption: U.S. Army Pan-American Flight, 26
    - Being made Illustration Guests of Arequipa [illegible] Hall, 27
    - Verso: Being made Illustration Guests of Arequipa [illegible] Hall, 27-verso
    - En route to Port au Prince, 28
    - Verso: En route to Port au Prince, 28-verso
    - Kingston, 29
    - Verso: Kingston, 29-verso
    - Caption: Raid Panamericans Puerto Cabello, Pto[?] de La Borburata donde Elegaron[?] aviones, 30
    - President of Honduras, his ministers + Mr. Sumerlin at U.S. legation [illegible], 31
    - Verso: President of Honduras, his ministers + Mr. Sumerlin at U.S. legation [illegible], 31-verso
    - A blown out tire coming ashore at [Fort de France?], 32
    - Verso: A blown out tire coming ashore at [Fort de France?], 32-verso
  - Subject files: Pan America flight (United States Army), 1926 - 1927; 22 (Box 1550)
    - [Pilot and plane of the United States Pan-American Flight; Caption: San Antonio at France Field, Damaged], 1
    - [Plane of the U.S. Army Pan-American Flight landing in water], 2
    - [Palm trees with plane in the water in the background; taken during the U.S. Pan-American Flight], 3
    - [United States Pan-American Flight plane landing; Caption: Pan American Plane at F.F. [France Field], 4
    - [United States Pan-American Flight plane landing in the water] Caption: Pan American Plane at FF. [France Field], 5
    - [U.S. Pan-American Flight plane in the water] Caption: Pan American Plane at FF. [France Field], 6
    - Caption: Pan American Plane at FF. [France Field], 7
    - [Pilots of the United States Pan American Flight working on their plane at France Field], 8
    - Caption: "San Antonio"damaged at France Field, 9
    - France Field, Dargue; Caption: "San Antonio"damaged at France Field, 10
    - Verso: France Field, Dargue, 10-verso
    - France Field, Dargue; Caption: "San Antonio"damaged at France Field, 11
    - Verso: France Field, Dargue, 11-verso
    - [Caption: "San Antonio"damaged at France Field; United States Pan-American Flight], 12
    - [U.S. Pan-American Flight plane in water], 13
    - [Body of water where planes from the Pan-American Flight landed], 14
    - [Pan-American Flight planes in air], 15
    - Caption: Pan-American plane at F.F. [France Field], 16
    - Caption: Pan-American plane at F.F. [France Field], 17
    - Caption: Pan-American plane at F.F. [France Field], 18
    - [Caption: San Antonio damaged at France Field], 19
    - Caption: "San Antonio" damaged at France Field, 20
    - France Field, Dargue; Caption: "San Antonio"damaged at France Field, 21
    - Verso: France Field, Dargue, 21-verso
    - Caption: San Antonio damaged at France Field, 22
    - France Field, Dargue, 23
    - Verso: France Field, Dargue, 23-verso
    - [Plane of the Pan American Flight in the water out in the distance], 24
    - Caption: Pan American Flight at F.F. [France Field], 25
    - Caltion: Amphibians taking off; Pan American Flight], 26
    - Caption: Pan American Plane at F.F. [France Field], 27
    - Caption: Pan American Plane at F.F. [France Field], 28
    - Caption: Pan American Plane at F.F. [France Field], 29
    - Caption: Pan American Plane at F.F. [France Field], 30
    - Caption: "San Antonio"damaged at France Field, Dargue, 31
    - Verso: France Field, Dargue, 31-verso
    - Captoin: "San Antonio" damaged at France Field, 32
    - Caption: "San Antonio" damaged at France Field, 33
    - Caption: San Antonio damaged at France Field, 34
    - [U.S. Pan American Flight plane in water], 35
    - France Field, Dargue, 36
    - Verso: France Field, Dargue, 36-verso